IDRIS JOVIAL SOP NWABO

Email: idrisjovisop@gmail.com
Cell Phone: +1 (438) 451-1169
Language: English & French

Address: 345 Barber Street, Ottawa, Canada

Professional Summary

Experienced Mobile Software Developer with over 9 years of experience in building Native iOS and Cross-Platform Mobile applications.

I have a strong technical skills set with an ability and experience to analyse and simplify complex problems using Software Engineering techniques and principles.

I have experience in managing projects, ensuring deliverables meet business requirements with assuring quality products and service delivery.

Willing to keep up to date with new technology.

Technical Skills & Knowledge

Mobile Software	PROGRAMMING	NETWORKING	Other Skills
Development	LANGUAGES &	& DATABASES	
	OTHERS		
iOS, Objective-C & Swift	Java, UML, JavaScript,	CISCO CCNA	Atlassian tools: Jira,
	Node.js, Angualr.js		Confluence, Bitbucket
Android Java & Kotlin (Basic)	C, C++	MySQL, SQL	Agile Methodology
Cross Platform Mobile	SVN, Firebase, Google	Router and Switch	Cloud Technologies:
Development	Analytics	Configuration	AWS, Azure
API RESTful Web services	Azure DevOps, TFS,	Linux, Bash	SourceTree, Postman,
JSON, SoapUI, XML	Git, GitLab, GitHub		Jenkins, Bamboo

Education and Professional Training

• January 2022 – December 2023: Postgraduate Diploma Digital Business

Wits Business School, Johannesburg, Gauteng, South Africa (Incomplete)

Modules: Digital Marketing, Business Strategy, Digital Technology Fundamentals, Digitalizing Operations, Digital Business in Africa, Digital Transformation, Innovation and Entrepreneurship, Intro to System Thinking, Customer Experience Management, Talent Management for Digital Leadership

- February 2016 December 2017: Advanced Diploma Business IT
 University of Johannesburg, Johannesburg, Gauteng, South Africa
- February 2012 December 2014: National Diploma Computer Systems

 Cape Peninsula University of technology Cape Town, Western Cape, South Africa

Professional Experience

Senior Mobile Developer (iOS)

October 2021 to Current

Standard Bank Group – Remote

- Develop, implement, maintain Standard Bank Mobile Banking Application using latest technologies stack and latest Design Pattern.
- Develop, implement, and manage new features and requirements in Mobile Card and Payment divisions.
- Drive relationship and collaboration with third party Companies such as Gemalto Thales, Tutuka, Apple Pay and drive integration with their APIs flow.
- Establish the required connectivity plan, setup, and configuration for third parties API SDK integration and implementation.
- Assist with testing apps and APIs in sandbox, Pre-Production and Production environment.
- Lead solutions and projects delivery and expectations.
- Ensure deliverables meet business requirements on time.
- Ensure quality products and services delivery.
- Analyze and handle and manage technical support and production incident.
- Manage team goals and expectations and apply Agile methodology such as Scrum.

Senior iOS & Mobile Software Developer

June 2019 to October 2021

Standard Bank Group – Simmonds, Johannesburg CyberPro Consulting Independent Contractor

- Develop, implement, maintain Standard Bank Mobile Banking Application using Native Apple programming languages such as Objective-C and Swift and latest Design Pattern.
- Develop, implement new features and requirements in Card Platform

iOS & Mobile Software Developer

November 2014 to May 2019

Dynamic Visual Technology (DVT) – Rosebank, Johannesburg

Based at **ABSA Group (From October 2017 to May 2019)**, a South African financial services provider my duties were:

- Develop, implement ABSA Mobile Banking Application using Native Apple programming languages such as Objective-C and Swift and latest Design Pattern.
- Develop, implement new features and requirements such as Payment, Wealth Investment and Management Insurance...
- Improve Software Applications using Software Engineering principles like SOLID principles.
- Integrate with third party systems using RESTful Web services (JSON & XML), APIs using Java.
- Apply Software architecture pattern (MVVM) and improve the design of the existing code.
- Optimize code based by writing Unit Tests using XCTest, Cuckoo.
- Ensure that deliverables meet business requirements on time.

Work with version control systems like Git, Bitbucket, Azure DevOps

Based at **Multichoice Africa (From November 2014 to September 2017)**, a large South African Telecommunication company my duties were:

- Develop, implement, deploy, support Native Corporate Mobile Applications using Objective-C, Swift and Java for SMA (Subscriber Management Application) Mobile
- Design, develop and implement Cross-Platform application using XML, JavaScript, CSS
- Integrate with MBaaS, Cloud Services such AWS, Kinvey, Google Firebase
- Create and Integrate with RESTful Web services,
- Geolocation Systems Implementation

iOS Software Developer Intern

March 2014 to October 2014

Fontera Digital Works – Green Point, Cape Town, Western Cape

- Design, develop and implement Native application for iPhone and iPad.
- Social Media integration into iOS App (Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Google+, Email)
- Interaction with third party systems using web service (JSON)
- Create and Integrate RESTful Web services, APIs using PHP.

Languages

English: Professional

• French: Fluent

Certifications

- iOS Development Architecture & Security
- ICAgile Certified Professional
- CISCO IT Specialist (CCNA 1 4)
- IT Essential, Server+, Data Cabling Fundamentals
- Computer Proficiency (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Access)